Deepak Malik

Automation Test Engineer | AI Enthusiast

+91-(829) 637-4058 | deepak164malik@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub

SUMMARY:

Software professional with 1.8 years of automation testing experience, specializing in regression test automation with Java Selenium. Proficient in front-end development and team collaboration. Currently expanding skills in Generative AI (GenAI) and eager to contribute to AI-driven projects.

Technical Skills & Certifications:

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript

• Automation Tools: Java Selenium

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

• Version Control: GitHub, GitHub copilot

• Project Management Tools: Rally

• Generative Al Technologies Framworks: LangChain

EXPERIENCE:

Programmer - Cognizant Feb 2023 - Nov 2024

- Collaborate with customers, engineering managers, developers, and business analysts to ensure timely and high-quality delivery of conversational channels that meet customer requirements.
- I successfully navigated diverse testing scenarios, showcasing adaptability to project requirements and technologies.
- Hands-on experience in API Testing (REST/SOAP).
- A collaborative team player, committed to delivering high-quality testing alignment with software development goals.
- Actively engaged in continuous learning and improvement, staying updated with industry best practices and emerging trends in quality assurance.

Freelance - Oct 2021 - Sep 2022

- Proficiently managed frontend websites using tools, such as HTML, CSS, and Nodejs and Researched blockchain to get in-depth knowledge of application
- Successfully resolved website bugs, leading to notable web functionality and speed improvements.
- Developed and implemented automated testing scripts in Python to assess the functionality of the platform.
- Leveraged Rainforest is an automation tool for effective UI testing and validation.
- Utilized CircleCl for seamless integration and automated execution of testing scripts.

PROJECTS:

UI Clone - Web Design

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS

- Designed a custom front end using TailwindCSS and CSS that is fully responsive to all devices
- Designed full-fledged end-to-end Paytm, Rode website, and Shopify UI clones.

Cognizant WebPage Functionality automation - Web Automation

Tech Stack: Java, Selenium

- Developed and maintained automated regression test suites for web applications using Java Selenium, improving testing efficiency and reducing manual effort by 30%.
- Designed and executed test cases to validate functionality, UI, and performance, ensuring adherence to client requirements and high-quality software delivery.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including developers and product owners, to identify test scenarios and resolve bugs, ensuring smooth project delivery.

EDUCATION:

New Horizon College (NHC), Bangalore July 2019 to Sep 2022 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Application